https://www.scoutingresources.org.uk/privacy/

Weather
What is Scouting?
Home
About Me
Navigation
What is Scouting?
Scouting Resources
We are committed to protecting your personal information. This page, together with our terms of use for this site and our cookies policy, set out the basis on which we will process any personal information we collect from you or that you provide to us.
Any questions regarding this privacy policy should sent by email to privacypolicy@scoutingingresources.org.uk
The types of information we collect
The only circumstances in which we will provide any of your personal data to a third party for non-commercial purposes are those contained in this Privacy Policy.
When you engage with us, for example, if you donate money, access our information or request services, or become involved, we may collect and process personal information about you. Depending on your activity, this personal information may include your name, email address, postal address, telephone or mobile number or date of birth.
We may also collect details of your visits to our website, including but not limited to traffic data, location data, weblogs, and other communication data and the resources that you access. By submitting this personal information you enable us to provide you with the information, services or products you select.
To help us create a more effective website that reflects users’ needs, we may also use cookie files to collect and record information about how our site is used and collect your IP address (a number that identifies a specific computer or other internet device) for system administration and to report aggregated information. Cookie files and IP addresses will not identify you as an individual. For more information on cookie files and IP addresses read our cookies policy at the bottom of this page, following the Privacy Policy. By continuing to use our site, you agree to our use of cookies.
How we may use your personal information
To provide you with information and services you have requested or which we feel may interest you where you have consented to being contacted. To allow you to participate in interactive features on our website, when you choose to do so, for example, we may help you complete forms by inserting your contact details for you to edit.
To analyse and improve the services offered on our websites by providing you with the most user-friendly navigation experience we can for your computer or other internet device.
With IP addresses, to identify your approximate location, block disruptive use or to establish the number of visits to the website from different countries.
We may share data supplied by you (or collected about you) with other parts of The Scout Association e.g. Scout Headquarters.
We review our retention periods for personal information on a regular basis.
We are legally required to hold some personal information to fulfil statutory obligations, for example the collection of Gift Aid or to support certain financial transactions. We will hold information about your details so that we can respect your preferences for being contacted by us.
How we handle your information and other organisations
Scoutingresources.org.uk will not rent or sell your personal information to other organisations for use by them in their own direct marketing activities.
However, where you have given us permission to contact you, we may use external service providers to do this on our behalf. An external service provider may, for example, include a fundraising agency calling on our behalf. We may ask external service providers to carry out tracking and analysis on our behalf as described in the cookies policy.
Where we use an external service provider to act on our behalf, we will disclose only the personal information necessary to deliver the service and will have a contract in place that requires the provider to comply with data protection and information security requirements.
We may disclose your personal information to third parties if we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation; or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use for this website or other agreements; or to protect the rights, property or safety of ScoutingResources or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud detection and protection.
Following links to third-party websites
This website may include links to other websites, not owned or managed by ScoutingResources. Whilst we try our best to only link to reputable websites we cannot be held responsible for the privacy of data collected by sites not managed by ScoutingResources, nor can we accept responsibility or liability for those policies. For this reason you should consult the privacy policy on any external website you link to before you submit any data to those websites.
Posting or sending content that you do not own
We have the right to disclose your identity to any third party claiming to own any content that you posted.
Where we store your information
Scoutingresources.org.uk may for financial or technical reasons from time to time need to use the services of an Internet Services Provider located outside of the European Economic Area.
However, at the moment ScoutingResources is hosted by Netweaver within the UK. ScoutingResources shall ensure that your personal information will be held by those Internet Service Providers in compliance with European data protection regulations. By submitting your personal information to our website, you agree to this transfer, storing or processing at a location outside the European Economic Area. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely and in accordance with this privacy policy.
In cases when we use external websites provided by other organisations such as Twitter or Facebook, then we would ask you to consult their privacy policies.
How to access your personal information
You have a right to know whether or not ScoutingResources holds any information about you (personal data) and a right to be provided with your information within 40 days in accordance with the Data Protection Act.
You can request your personal information by email to privacypolicy@scoutingingresources.org.uk
We do not make a charge for this. It will help us to find your information if you can tell us something about the nature of your contact with us.
We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate.
Updates or changes to the privacy policy
We reserve the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy. Each time you visit this site you should check this Privacy Policy to check that no changes have been made to any sections that are important to you.
Where appropriate, any changes will be notified to you by email.
Contacting us
If you want to contact us to raise any questions about this privacy statement, or any general matters relating to scoutingresources.org.uk, you can contact us using this email address: Any questions regarding this privacy policy should sent by email to privacypolicy@scoutingingresources.org.uk
Please use this address if you wish to request from us a copy of the personal data we hold about you. Please note that under English law we are entitled to charge you a fee for providing this service.
Cookies Policy
A cookie is a small piece of data (which often includes a unique identifier) that is stored on your computer, mobile phone or tablet. It is generated when users access a certain website. The cookie is stored on your browser and then sent back to the originating website on each subsequent visit. Cookies that are generated through the use of this website are not used to identify you personally but they are used to make the site work better for you by remembering activities and preferences chosen by you and your browser. Cookies are used to improve the quality of your website experience by:
Enabling a service to recognise your device so that you do not have to repeat any unnecessary actions
Measuring how many people are using our website services, and from where in the world they visit us. This enables us to tailor content more closely to the profile of our users.
Cookies might also be used occasionally to help gather feedback to help us understand how users interact with specific services, to inform future website development plans.
ypes of cookies
Cookies can be categorised from their life span:
Session or temporary cookies: these cookies expire when you close your browser or when the session times out
Persistent or permanent cookies: these are usually stored on your hard disk and survive across multiple sessions but have a longer expiration date
However if you wish to control, block or delete any cookies which are generated by this website, or indeed any other website, you can do so through your browser settings. The “help” function on your browser will provide relevant instructions.
Please be aware that restricting cookies may impact on the functionality of our website.
Alternatively you may wish to visit the About Cookies website which provides comprehensive information on how to control cookies through a variety of different browsers. http://www.aboutcookies.org/
Copyright © 2018 Scouting Resources | All Rights Reserved
Design by 1234.info | Modified by Darren Dowling | Powered by Netweaver | XHTML 1.0 | CSS 2.0 | Privacy Policy | Privacy Policy| Privacy Policy
